Finding Aid for Bureau of Appointments and Occupational Information (University of Michigan), records, 1905-1930
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Bureau of Appointments and Occupational Information (University of Michigan) records 1905-1930
University of Michigan. Bureau of Appointments and Occupational Information.
11 linear feet
8735 Bimu C476 2
Records, 1905-1930, of the Bureau of Appointments and Occupational Information of the University of Michigan. Contain placement records of the Bureau of Appointments, including biographical data, employment and educational history, recommendations, and photographs of applicants.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The source of the transfer of this record group is unknown NO.
The record group is open without restriction
The first Bureau of Appointments was created in 1898 by the faculty of Literature, Science and the Arts to aid graduates in finding teaching positions. In 1906, this bureau became part of the Department of Education within the Literary College. In 1926, the president appointed a committee on vocational guidance and placement that conducted research on occupations and characteristics of individual students, and started a placement service. In 1929, the two units were combined under the directorship of T. Luther Purdom as the Bureau of Appointments and Occupational Information. The bureau continued until 1952.
The records contain placement records of the Bureau of Appointments, including biographical data, employment and educational history, recommendations, and photographs of applicants. Also included is composite data of placements by the bureau.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Bureau of Appointments.; University of Michigan. Bureau of Appointments and Occupational Information.; University of Michigan. Committee on Vocational Counsel and Placement.; University of Michigan--Students--Employment.; University of Michigan--Students.; College placement services--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Placement Records
  - 1905 (Box 1)
  - 1906 (Box 1)
  - 1907 (Box 1)
  - 1908-1912 (Box 1)
  - 1908 (Box 1)
  - Record Book, 1909-1916 (Box 2)
  - 1909 (Box 2)
  - 1910 (Box 2)
  - 1911 (Box 2)
  - 1912 (Box 3)
  - 1913 (Box 3)
  - 1914 (Box 3)
  - 1915 (Box 4)
  - 1916 (Box 4)
  - 1917 (Box 4)
  - 1918 (Box 5)
  - 1919 (Box 5)
  - 1920 (Box 5)
  - 1921 (Box 6)
  - 1922 (Box 6)
  - 1923
    - A-K (Box 6)
    - L-Z (Box 7)
  - 1924 A-J (Box 7)
  - 1925 (Box 7)
  - 1926 I-Z (Box 8)
  - 1927 (Box 8)
  - 1928 (Box 9)
  - 1929
    - A-K (Box 9)
    - L-Z (Box 10)
  - 1930 (Box 10)
- Records of Geographical Location of Candidates
  - Michigan (Box 11)
  - U. S. (Box 11)
  - Foreign (Box 11)
  - U.S. Government (Box 11)
- Speeches
  - Thomas L. Purdom, concerning Personnel Research Work, 1928 (Box 11)